Anthony P. Conte

PERSONAL SUMMARY

A 14 year plus seasoned Information Technology professional with Corporate IT, Project and Security Management experience participating in planning, analysis implementation of Core Networks, and information-security solutions in direct support. First-class analytical design and problem solving skills dedicated and committed to maintaining the highest quality of standards.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- · Project management
- · Staff development
- · Information security
- HTML 5, CSS, Javascript, Sitecore
- · Remote Access

- Data Analysis
- · Network Troubleshooting
- Performance Optimization
- · Hardware and software configurations
- Active Directory

· Much More

- · IT Performance Report Creation
- · Infrastructure planning and design

WORK EXPERIENCE

State of CT DESPP Hartford CT

INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY ANALYST January 2018 - September 2021

- Pushed updates [Windows application updates and security] to departmental user's machines via System Center Configuration
 Manager, and McAfee Endpoint Encryption.
- Used Active Directory to create accounts, unlock and disable accounts as needed. Also Reset passwords and applied permissions.
- · Performed regular updates to the CJIS website
- Successfully facilitated the data migration to a new Learning Management System for our users.
- · Successfully implemented the deployment and imaging of new machines within department
- Helped lead the facilitation of remote work for staff during the Covid-19 pandemic.
- Provided on-demand service via email and phone calls to over 4,000 end users.
- Regularly produced knowledge base articles for CJIS internal IT staff.
- Resolved malfunctions with systems and programs through troubleshooting

Dragados USA New York NY

IT INFRASTRUCTURE MANAGER February 2014 - December 2017

- · Manage and directed the operations of the Corporate Technology Department.
- · Support multiple locations and field offices throughout USA and Canada.
- · Manage vendor relationships, service contracts and Infrastructure purchases for the organization, affiliates and joint ventures.
- Administered the Corporate IT SharePoint Server Libraries and documentation.
- · Proposed new LAN/WAN solution with high availability.
- Create plan to migrate all affiliate resources into Dragados-USA data center.
- Examined, recommended and create plan to reconfigure the existing Hyper-V virtual infrastructure.
- Create plan to reconfigured the user's network, Researched and recommend new infrastructure solution to improve network and server performance.
- · Researched and implemented a new Backup solution.

Jolly Airtime LLC. New York NY

IT SYSTEM SPECIALIST February 2011 - January 2014

- · Fielded user requests and queries to deliver troubleshooting services and implement corrective actions.
- Capitalized on industry and marketplace trends to strategize solutions and enhance business operations
- Administered and maintained cloud deployment
- Worked with software development team on reported errors and bugs on newly released software and assisted in deployment of release fixes
- Installed, update, and maintain flight, hotel and third party services price aggregation software.
- Maintained problem resolution procedures, tracking QA support to document and address IT deviations and monitor information system performance.
- Supported IT inspections based on internal and regulatory requirements.
- Performed data backups and disaster recovery operations
- Installed wiring, cabling and devices to establish, repair and improve network operations.
- Configured hardware devices and software settings to optimize network performance
- Updated and reconfigured existing and new computers with current software and operating systems.
 Imaged OS and software deployments throughout system and addressed implementation concerns.
- Evaluated local area network [LAN] and wide area network [WAN] performance data to verify availability and speed, identifying network problems.
- Compiled trend reports to proactively assess technology issues and threshold compliance.

EDUCATION

University of Connecticut, Storrs CT - Master of Science: Information Management And Technology

University of Connecticut, Storrs CT - Bachelor of Science: Computer Science And Data Analytics & Data -

Katherine Gibbs College, Norwalk CT - Associates of Science: Computer Networking -

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Microsoft Azure Fundamentals Certification Number: 1005-7798
- CompTIA A+ Certification ID: COMP001021057034
- Google IT Support Professional Certificate